Chi (Violet) Zhang



violet1004zc@gmail.com



+64 02108976758



in linkedin.com/in/chi-zhang-7b16b9284



https://violetzzzzzz.github.io/myweb/

SUMMARY

I am a graduate of the Master of Software Development Program at Victoria University of Wellington. Throughout my academic journey, I have developed a solid understanding of various programming languages, including Java, PHP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Through practical experiences, I have expanded my skill set to include C#, Python, React, TypeScript, and MySQL through diverse projects.

I am excited about the prospect of applying these technical skills, combined with my communication and negotiation abilities developed through my experience in early childhood education, to a future role in the IT industry.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Front-end: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, JavaFX, Tkinter
- Back-end: Java, C# (.NET, ASP.NET, MAUI.NET), PHP, Python
- Database: SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, AWS RDS
- Version Control: Git (GitHub, GitLab)
- IDE & Tools: Visual Studio, VS Code, IntelliJ IDEA, Eclipse, Android Studio
- Agile & Project Management: Scrum, Kanban, Jira
- UI/UX: Figma, Balsamiq

SOFT SKILLS

- Effective Communication and Collaboration
- My prior teaching experience has honed my effective communication and collaboration skills, interacting with tamariki, kaiako, and whanau.
- Problem Solving and Adaptability
- I excel in problem-solving and have seamlessly adapted from medicine research to teaching and software development. This journey, marked by extensive self-learning, highlights my proactive approach to problem-solving and adaptability.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

- Bhakti Lounge Door Check-in and Management System (Volunteer Project)
- Apr 2024 Present
- React, ASP.NET Core, Vite
- I developed and integrated the front-end with back-end APIs for the Bhakti Lounge check-in system, including client communication, prototype design, and main check-in page development. I also maintain the system, implementing UI/UX improvements and API enhancements.
- A Canvas Module: a real-time, interactive whiteboard-style interface (Academic-Industry Collaboration Project)
- React, TypeScript, JavaScript, C#

- I contributed to the development of a 2D animated sprite that moves with the cursor on the canvas, allowing real-time position sharing with other users working on the same canvas.
- Secure Text Document Encryption and Decryption Software (Academic)
- Java, JavaFX, AWS RDS MySQL
- A project that allows users to type text or upload files for encryption or decryption. It also has authentication feature and uses AWS RDS to store data.
- Contact List (Academic)
- Version 1: .NET MAUI, C#, MySQL. Version 2: Python, Tkinter, MySQL
- A contact list that allows users to manage contacts, and it has authentication feature and uses AWS RDS MySQL to store data.
- An Online Image Gallery (Academic)
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL
- An online image gallery that allows user to create their albums and add photos.

EDUCATION

Master of Software Development

- -07/2023 6/2024
- Level of Award: Distinction

Victoria University of Wellington, New Zealand

Graduate Diploma of Early Childhood Teaching

- 05/2019 - 05/2020

New Zealand Tertiary College, Auckland, New Zealand

Bachelor of Pharmacy

- 09/2014 - 06/2018

Sichuan University, Sichuan, China

WORK EXPERIENCE

Registered Reliever Teacher

- 08/2024 - present

Jitbug / Dynamic ECE Limited, Wellington

Registered Early Childhood Teacher

- 08/2020 - 07/2023

Educare Tawa, Tawa, Wellington

Reliever Early Childhood Teacher

- 07/2019 - 07/2020

Beststart, Meadowbank, Auckland

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Badminton, Hiking, Jazz & K-pop Dance, Snorkelling, Painting, Crafts, Steam and Board Game.

References available upon request